{
  "exam_name": "Computer Architecture Exam.pdf",
  "problem": "1",
  "parts": [
    {
      "part": "a",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "For the following four numbers given in decimal or hexadecimal notation, write the corresponding binary number using the indicated format.\n\n(−11)10 using 6-bit two's complement: (11 0101)2\n\n(51)10 using 6-bit unsigned: (11 0011)2\n\n(−17)10 using 6-bit sign magnitude: (11 0001)2\n\n(39)16 using 6-bit unsigned: (11 1001)2",
          "subproblem_figures": []
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "Zero is represented twice (+0, -0), and more importantly subtraction is more complex when you have sign/magnitude. In two's complement the same circuit can handle both positive and negative numbers exactly the same way.",
          "solution_figures": []
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "part": "b",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "What are the problems with the sign/magnitude representation of binary numbers, why are they not used more often than two's complement representation?",
          "subproblem_figures": []
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "Zero is represented twice (+0, -0), and more importantly subtraction is more complex when you have sign/magnitude. In two's complement the same circuit can handle both positive and negative numbers exactly the same way.",
          "solution_figures": []
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}

{
  "exam_name": "Computer Architecture Exam.pdf",
  "problem": "2",
  "problem_context": "A circuit has four inputs (A, B, C, D) and two outputs (E, T ).\n\n• Output E should be '1' if there are equal number of '1's and '0's in the input.\n\n• Output T should be '1' if two or more of the inputs are '1'",
  "problem_figures": [],
  "parts": [
    {
      "part": "a",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "Complete the following truth table",
          "subproblem_figures": ["TABLE"]
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "",
          "solution_figures": []
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "part": "b",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "Write a Boolean equation for E using either SOP or POS representation. (Hint: use a Karnaugh map)",
          "subproblem_figures": []
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "One possible solution is:\nE = (A ·B ·C ·D) + (A ·B ·C ·D) + (A ·B ·C ·D) + (A ·B ·C ·D) + (A ·B · C ·D) + (A ·B · C ·D)",
          "solution_figures": []
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "part": "c",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "Write a Boolean equation for T using either SOP or POS representation. (Hint: use a Karnaugh map)",
          "subproblem_figures": []
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "One possible solution is:\nT = (A ·B) + (A · C) + (A ·D) + (B · C) + (B ·D) + (CḊ)",
          "solution_figures": []
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "part": "d",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "Draw a gate level diagram implementing T using only two-input AND, OR gates and/or inverters.",
          "subproblem_figures": []
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "",
          "solution_figures": ["IMAGE"]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "part": "e",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "Assuming that the propagation of all 2-input gates and inverters is 100 ps and the contamination delay is 50 ps, what is the critical path (longest path), and the shortest path of the circuit you have drawn in Question 2d?",
          "subproblem_figures": []
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "For the solution given in Question 2d, the critical path goes through 1 AND gate and 3 OR gates = 4 propagation delays = 400ps.\nThe shortest path goes through one AND gate and two OR gates = 3 contamination delays = 150ps.",
          "solution_figures": []
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "part": "f",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "Note that the function T contains E (meaning T is '1' for every input that results in a '1' for E). Assume that you already have a small circuit that implements E, design a simpler Boolean function that implements T by using the output of E and draw the gate level schematic once again only using E, 2-input AND/OR gates and inverters.",
          "subproblem_figures": []
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "One of the simpler solutions is: T = (A ·D) + (B · C) + E",
          "solution_figures": ["IMAGE"]
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}

{
  "exam_name": "Computer Architecture Exam.pdf",
  "problem": "3",
  "problem_context": "In this question you will be given the state transition diagram for a Finite State Machine (FSM). The FSM has a two-bit output \"out[1:0]\" as well as a single bit input \"in\".",
  "problem_figures": ["IMAGE"],
  "parts": [
    {
      "part": "a",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "Is this a Mealy or Moore type of FSM, briefly explain why?",
          "subproblem_figures": []
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "This is a Mealy type of FSM, as the output depends not only on the state but also on the present value of the input.",
          "solution_figures": []
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "part": "b",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "Using the following state encoding table, complete the state transition and output table on the following page.",
          "subproblem_figures": ["TABLE", "TABLE"]
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "",
          "solution_figures": []
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "part": "c",
      "subproblem": [
        {
          "subproblem_question": "Draw a new state transition diagram for this FSM using a different type (if the original was a Moore, then draw a Mealy type or vice versa) that has the same functionality.",
          "subproblem_figures": []
        }
      ],
      "answer": [
        {
          "solution": "This is one possible solution. Note that states ZeroA and ZeroB can be merged, however this organization is slightly more regular, and shows the thinking behind the original FSM.",
          "solution_figures": ["IMAGE"]